Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
I can cut a thousand strands of hair
but I cannot sever the tangled threads of my mind.
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
You failed me.
Imperial Mother.
You promised me...
After the concubine selection...
Don't cry. Imperial Mother is still here.
Imperial Mother and His Majesty must
have much to say to each other.
Let's take our leave and wait outside.
Where is the 14th Prince?
Why can't I see the 14th Prince?
Imperial Mother, you're confused.
I don't have much time left.
Could you let me see the 14th Prince?
Imperial Mother, although you gave birth to me,
I was raised by Empress Xiaoyiren.
Unlike the 14th Prince who you raised yourself.
I spent less time by your side.
At this moment, just let me be here with you.
You still won't show mercy on the 14th Prince?
I know your temper.
So I never mentioned it,
nor did I dare to.
But now, know that I am begging you...
please, let your brother go.
Imperial Mother,
you needn't concern yourself about court matters.
Emperor,
you imprisoned your imperial relatives,
and killed your brothers who were like "arms and legs" to you,
not even sparing your own brother.
Your own kin won't acknowledge you,
as if your "flesh and bones had been severed."
Those deeds were not my own choice;
they forced them upon me.
From a humbly-ranked new concubine,
I became a Consort step by step.
For myself,
for your throne,
I exhausted every ingenious scheme.
Now that I am old,
should I just watch all of you
killing each other?
Imperial Mother,
You need not worry about these trivial things anymore.
The late emperor is watching from above.
How you treated your own brother,
how you contended for the throne -
the late emperor has seen everything!
My plans to gain the throne ...
you were involved in every move all along.
The relationship between you and Longkodo -
I refrained from speaking about it.
I wholeheartedly loved Empress Première,
and I treat her sister Yixiu well.
I'm already extremely filial!
Some words
should never be spoken again.
As your son, I'm indebted to you for
taking care of Longkodo in my stead,
saving me from having a bad name.
Imperial Mother.
"Sleep fast and you will grow up."
"The bowstring will sing in your hands when you grow up..."
You’ve never...
never sung...
such a nursery rhyme to me.
Can you sing to me once,
Imperial Mother?
Kneel.
First bow.
Second bow.
Third bow.
Mourn.
- Why did you come back from the Palace of Imperial Longevity?
- Mother.
I heard Imperial Father is grieving.
I’m so worried for him.
Come here.
Although your Imperial Father is grieving,
his grief is natural, not a primary concern.
Then I should be less worried.
You are the one that worries me.
It’s hot these days,
and your Imperial Father persists in vigil,
and has fainted several times.
You’re now the most sensible prince of all.
How much blame will you arouse
if you don’t stay there on behalf of your father?
I'm witless.
I just wanted to check on Imperial Father.
Your filial duty in the mourning hall
is more important than any ginseng soup.
This is "the thought of a lady."
Don’t focus too much on trivial matters.
Yes.
I will stay at the Palace of Imperial Longevity on your behalf.
Come after you have left the ginseng soup.
Imperial Father.
I’m here to pay my respects.
Everything is taken care of at the Palace of Imperial Longevity.
Please take your time to recuperate and don't worry about anything.
His Majesty the Emperor.
Peace to Your Majesty.
Rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
Today is the Lantern Festival.
I come here after meeting the court officials.
The paths are slippery on a snowy day.
Your Majesty's servants should be more careful.
Along the way here,
I see nothing for the festival is overly luxurious.
Very good. Take your seats.
I thank Your Majesty.
It hasn't been long since the Empress Dowager departed this world.
I thought it would be best to keep everything simple.
It also shows our filial affection.
I agree with you.
Noble Consort Lumière,
have Hongyan and Lingxi been sleeping well?
Do they have a good appetite?
Does Jinghe still cry a lot?
All is going well at the Imperial Nursery.
The maids take meticulous care of them.
Your Majesty sees these three children every day,
yet still gets concerned about them.
You're a very loving father!
It's not only His Majesty,
as their mother,
even though I am with them daily,
I still have too much to worry about.
Of course, Noble Consort Lumière has to take care of so many things.
It makes her look less healthy.
You're a mother after all,
You have to take everything into serious consideration
Your Majesty is the "mother of the nation."
You are the mother of all the citizens under Heaven.
Your Majesty has many more matters to worry about than I do.
The Empress has not been a birth mother for many years.
Naturally, she cannot recall how tiring and difficult it is
to take care of young children.
Why are you bowing so suddenly?
Congratulations, Your Majesty.
Concubine An from the Palace of Prolonging Happiness
has been pregnant for three months.
Really?
The Doctor has already taken her pulse.
It is as true as can be.
Congratulations, Your Majesty!
Congratulations, Concubine An!
Please sit down, all sit.
Your Majesty discreetly hid all information about this,
announcing it only after Concubine An's pregnancy became stable.
Your Majesty's thoughtfulness is profound.
Concubine An has always had a fragile constitution.
Her "monthly letters" were usually irregular.
She herself didn't know that she was pregnant
until she was three months along.
Her father is still in prison.
She doesn't dare to draw any attention.
I also concealed the truth as a precaution.
Just in case any concubine was overcome by jealousy
and went down Consort Astuce's old path.
Precisely, Your Majesty.
Since I was decreed to assist in palace affairs,
I will do everything to aid Your Majesty
to protect Concubine An's imperial heir.
Noble Consort Lumière always considers the greater good.
Nothing is more appreciated.
Your Majesty, Concubine An is frail
and deeply worried about her father at the same time.
For the stability of her pregnancy and to comfort her,
I plead with Your Majesty to promote Concubine An to Consort.
There can be four Consorts in the palace.
However...
I am also thinking on behalf of the future heir.
If she is not promoted, I'm concerned
the palace gossip will focus on
how Concubine An was negatively impacted by her father's case.
That will make her even sadder.
How will she stabilize her pregnancy?
Her Majesty is determined.
Concubine An's title has always been simply her family name.
Since she now carries a future heir, her status is more distinguished.
To demonstrate sincerity and the significance of the promotion,
the Household Department should take care
proposing some honorary names.
That is very thoughtful of you, Noble Consort Lumière.
We will have the Imperial Household Department do it.
Many ranks are not occupied currently for Consort and above.
It's a blessing to fulfill the number at the Consort level.
Is Your Highness feeling unwell?
How could An Lingrong become pregnant?
Indeed...
Didn't she already use the Flesh Thinning Pills?
How could she be pregnant?
Although the pills were harmful to her body,
it doesn't mean she was made infertile.
This has lifted the Empress's spirits.
Today the Empress once again mentioned
An Lingrong's father's case and her prenatal care.
In order to protect the imperial heir,
An Bihuai's bribe-taking records might soon be erased.
If An Lingrong gives birth to a prince,
then the Empress will have two sons in her palm.
No matter which one is established as the Crown Prince,
our situation in the palace will....
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
What brings you here? Rise.
Indeed "a blithe heart makes a blooming visage!"
I can easily tell
how much joy Lingrong's pregnancy brings to Your Majesty
from Your Majesty's glowing appearance.
I always knew Lingrong had a delicate constitution.
But surprisingly, her pregnancy is quite stable.
That shows how caring the baby is -
he will be so filial and sensible when he grows up.
You came at a good time,
I was quite bored reading by myself.
I was thinking
Your Majesty must've had a really good appetite at lunch
from the joy over Lingrong's pregnancy.
If so, Your Majesty's stomach must feel overly full now,
so I brought special desserts for Your Majesty.
What does Your Majesty think？
Our hearts are connected by the "divine rhino's horn".
This lotus soup is made from fresh young lotus leaves
picked before sunrise.
The water for the soup was taken from dewdrops on the lotus leaves.
It was collected last year.
The lotus osmanthus cakes are fragrant and sweet.
May Your Majesty try some.
I remember that
Meizhuang used to make the most delicious lotus osmanthus cakes.
Enjoying the cakes is reminding
Your Majesty of Meizhuang.
Your Majesty must miss her.
Peace to Your Majesty.
Peace to Your Noble Highness.
What is it?
Your Majesty,
the Household Department proposed several honorary names for Concubine An
for Your Majesty's review.
Why don't you help review them?
All three words have a good meaning.
The Sù character
can mean one is virtuous and principled,
as well as dutiful and deferential.
But in my opinion, the Wén character
is more suitable for Lingrong's temperament.
Lingrong is soft-spoken and humble.
She is indeed a courteous person.
The Wén character is more appropriate.
Although Wén can be interpreted as "gentle and well-mannered",
more often than not,
it describes someone who is well-read and cultured.
If this character is selected,
Lingrong might overthink.
That leaves us with the character Lì.
Lì means
a beautiful appearance,
and it implies a twosome or pair,
because the word Kàng Lì refers to a loving husband and wife.
This is the best.
Your Majesty, is there something wrong?
Concubine An is only my concubine.
How can she be considered my wife?
If I choose to give her this name,
the officials will have a lot to criticize,
saying I overly favor this concubine.
Su Peisheng.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Inform the Household Department
that these characters are not befitting.
They need to select new ones.
Yes.
Actually, why trouble the Household Department again?
If Your Majesty assigns a name for Lingrong,
that would be the best.
I can't think of a name right now,
how about you think of one for me?
How am I qualified to make such a decision?
Here, you can write first and I'll have a look.
If it isn't suitable, I'll change it.
Your Majesty, what do you think?
Lí [oriole].
Adept at singing and dancing,
with a gentle disposition like an oriole.
Besides, orioles are birds of lasting affection.
Your Majesty, I heard that orioles are very prolific.
Now that Concubine An is with child -
"The more children, the more happiness."
Hmm.
In this way, it is a good name.
Su Peisheng, announce the decree
and request that the Empress choose an auspicious date.
Aye.
Master, what happened today?
You look so happy.
Concubine An received a good title.
How can I not be happy?
Request fifty orioles from the Imperial Aviary.
Let's go congratulate Concubine An.
Aye.
What are you thinking about, so absorbed?
This great day of rejoicing for Lingrong
reminded me of how we entered the harem together.
Lingrong, Meizhuang, and I
entered the palace on the same day.
We've always been like sisters.
I didn't treat Meizhuang well when she was alive.
Looking back, it disturbs my heart.
Now, I already rank at Noble Consort
and Lingrong is titled Consort Oriole.
Although Meizhuang was promoted to Consort Vertu,
her posthumous name still remains undecided.
I wish to ask for Your Majesty's grace:
please grant Meizhuang a posthumous honor.
The dead have passed on.
There are not many things the living can do for them.
I will do as you suggest to convey our reminiscence.
The Empress is unwell. I will entrust this to you.
Yes.
Since we speak of this matter,
I'm boldly taking the liberty of asking for another favor.
Consort Astuce committed suicide to escape punishment.
Customarily, she cannot be conferred a title posthumously.
But as the Third Prince grows up,
his prestige should be considered.
In this case, I will confer honor on all the late concubines.
Nian Gengyao and Longkodo were executed.
I don't want people to say that I am also harsh to my concubines.
Noble Consort Fleur is honored as Imperial Noble Consort.
This will be an expression of my sorrowfulness.
Speaking of honors,
I remember what Her Majesty said today
in The Palace of Great Benevolence.
Her Majesty said
many of the harem ranks are not currently occupied.
I have thought the same thing.
The harem has no lack of concubines
more senior and more virtuous than me.
I often feel self-conscious and uneasy
sitting in such a high rank.
Now that you mention it, the harem hasn't had
an extensive promotion for a long time.
I'd have almost forgotten it if the Empress didn't mention it.
I think so too.
The late concubines are not the highest priority.
However, the concubines we face day to day
should be granted their due promotions.
A harmonious harem is conducive
to Your Majesty in the imperial court.
I only have one request:
No matter how Your Majesty promotes the concubines,
please grant Consort Honnête the highest honor
and place her above me.
Otherwise, I will always feel uneasy.
Consort Honnête was the first to enter the harem,
she is worthy of the title of Imperial Noble Consort.
However, I am of the mind that this title belongs to you.
I understand that Your Majesty has me in your heart.
I don't mind any rank and title.
If so, Consort Honnête is promoted to Imperial Noble Consort.
I also let Consort Estime suffer a lot in the earlier years.
She's mild-tempered and gentle.
I will promote her to Noble Consort - the same rank as yours.
And, Noble Lady Joie has been serving me for many years.
She is promoted to Concubine Joie.
Your Majesty is considerate of everyone.
I could never be mindful of so many things.
You're not inconsiderate -
you were just waiting for me to open my mouth.
You've made so many requests for others,
Why not ask for something for yourself?
I am favored by Your Majesty.
That is the greatest grace.
I don't need anything else.
Noble Consort Lumiere wants
the Ministry of Rites and our department to
arrange the ceremony for the harem's grand promotions.
Over the coming days,
you need to be doubly careful in your duties.
This is a grand celebration in the palace.
Don't do anything wrong.
Aye.
Have you seen the list of the promoted concubines?
Moving forward,
you need to be aware of whose words count in the harem now.
I'm telling you,
any task for the Palace of Eternal Longevity is the number one priority.
Thank you, sir, for your instructions.
Now then,
who undertook the job to propose an honorary name for Concubine An?
- It was me.
You want to curry favor,
but you need to know who you're fawning on
and whether you should do so.
These two!
Will be pulled outside and flogged forty times each.
Then throw them into the Department of Penalty.
- Aye.
-Sir, I meant no offense!
- Go.
- I am wrongfully convicted.
Concubine An is now titled Consort Oriole.
It seems that she's gaining favor.
But if you curry favor blindly,
you may offend others without knowing.
Then you deserve to be flogged to death.
Aye.
My Lady, you have to cheer up.
Please consider the prince in your belly.
Although I have been promoted to Consort,
why am I named after a bird?
Why were the eunuchs who drafted the titles flogged?
Why were they sent to the Department of Justice?
Maybe they performed other tasks improperly.
What else can it be?
It was only because of me!
They chose several good titles for me and then were flogged.
Doesn't that tell the whole harem to treat me poorly?
Who dares?
My Lady, you're pregnant with an imperial heir.
The Household Department delivers all the best supplies to you.
They wouldn't dare to send anything that's not the best.
I'm not unaware.
It is only because of my pregnancy.
If I lose this child....
My Lady, you mustn't say that.
What's the noise outside? It's giving me a headache!
Get them out!
Get them all out!
My Lady. My Lady.
They are sent by Mr. Su
to congratulate you on your promotion.
Mr. Su probably did it on behalf of His Majesty.
My Lady, you can't make His Majesty think
you dislike the title he granted.
Get them out! Get them all out!
Get them all out! You heard me!
- My Lady.
- Get them out!
I don't want to hear them!
Translators: The O̶r̶i̶o̶l̶e̶ Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊(鹂)桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Where are all these orioles from?
Where else could it be?
Most likely from Consort Oriole's palace.
I lifted her too high.
She must be aware that
despite her higher rank, she doesn't deserve it.
She doesn't indeed.
She dared to praise the titles proposed by the Household Department.
The character Lì can only be used by the Empress,
to show deep conjugal love with the Emperor.
Consort Oriole is not well-read; yet dares
to comment on a character she doesn't understand.
Zhen Huan is taking all the benefits from the harem-wide promotions.
Let her feel smug for a few days.
Your Majesty is wise.
Did the doctors send the prenatal tonics on time?
Per Your Majesty's order,
only the best tonics.
Last night, the doctors reported that
to stabilize Consort Oriole's prenatal qi,
they already started burning mugwort leaves.
Burning mugwort already in the fourth month...
The pregnancy must be hard on her body.
She has been obedient these years,
taking the medicine and foregoing pregnancy.
Now she listens to Your Majesty
and took the fertility herbs.
She has already received the blessing
of carrying "the dragon's child" for a few months.
Tell the imperial doctors to do whatever they must
to make her pregnancy
appear safe and sound.
Yes.
That's it for today's mugwort burning.
Your Highness must
take the prenatal medicine on time every day,
to ensure nothing goes amiss.
Additionally,
Your Highness must maintain a light heart
for your safety during the pregnancy.
I will come back in three days
to burn mugwort again, to stabilize Your Highness's pregnancy.
I will take my leave now.
Take care, doctor.
Coua,
go dump the mugwort residue from this bowl.
We mustn't let people notice the odor of burnt mugwort.
Yes.
Your Highness,
the news that His Majesty is granting extensive promotions
is spreading everywhere.
Once Her Majesty mentioned Consort Oriole's promotion,
Your Highness proposed harem-wide promotions.
Now everybody
is waiting to thank Your Highness.
I don't want to let the Empress be the only good person.
She wants to promote An Linrong.
I am merely "pushing a boat already being carried by the current."
Good things are meant to be shared.
Keeping what I want
while cutting what I see as redundant.
Pruning the flower branches is just like
sorting out the Harem.
I understand this.
Her Majesty understands it even more.
The flower branches have been pruned very well.
Flowers and leaves are like people.
They can grow out sideways at any time.
We must stay observant.
Your Highness is right.
Your Highness.
The bird's nest soup is ready for Your Highness.
Isn't it always red bird's nest?
Why is it white bird's nest today?
The Household Department said that Her Majesty decreed
that because Consort Oriole is pregnant,
the red bird's nest will be provided only
to the Palace of Prolonging Happiness.
All other palaces shall have only white bird's nest for now.
Her Majesty cherishes Consort Oriole so endearingly.
If she truly wants to reward her, it doesn't have to be so obvious.
Just ask the Household Department to send it daily.
But she gives all of it to her,
which will raise complaints in the harem.
That's the shrewdness of the Empress.
On one hand,
it reminds Consort Oriole not to forget
Her Majesty's favors.
On the other hand, Consort Oriole already has many enemies in the palace.
The more favor she gains,
the more people envy and resent her.
To protect herself and the child in her belly,
she can only cling more tightly to "the big tree."
But it appears that
the rift between them is not a small one.
By the grace of Heaven, His Majesty decrees:
"Consort Honnête is promoted to Imperial Noble Consort"
"and Consort Estime to Noble Consort Estime."
"Together with Noble Consort Lumiere, they will oversee palace affairs."
"Concubine An is promoted to Consort Oriole,"
"Noble Lady Joie to Concubine Joie,"
"Noble Lady Paix to Concubine Paix,"
"Attendant Lustré to Noble Lady Lustré."
This is His Majesty's edict.
I thank His Majesty for the heavenly grace.
The music and dancing can be heard now.
I suppose the promotion ceremony has just finished.
It's better you didn't go, My Lady.
You can't go to crowded places while pregnant.
Because I'm not worth it.
Please don't think like that, My Lady.
Her Majesty was considerate of you.
The weather is getting hot;
it's not suitable for you to go to crowded places.
Considerate?
Even the dead Shen Meizhuang got promoted.
Is His Majesty slapping me in the face?
Please don't say that.
It's taboo for "the dragon's child."
Why?
Dead people don't matter.
I'm worried that His Majesty is making
an implication about Meizhuang's death.
Please don't take it to heart.
After all, His Majesty detested Noble Consort Fleur,
and she still got a posthumous promotion to Imperial Noble Consort.
His Majesty is just afraid of people talking.
Besides, it would have been difficult to
turn down a request made in person....
Don't worry, My Lady.
His Majesty has pardoned Mr. An.
He was also awarded a hundred taels of gold
so he can retire to his hometown.
That shows how much His Majesty cares about you.
Once this is over,
all my effort to carry this child for months won't be wasted.
Am I late? What a lively crowd here.
Lumière, you're here.
Lie down.
Now that you're pregnant,
all you need to do is rest.
Coua, serve my pre-rain Longjing tea.
I suppose Noble Consort Lumiere will like it.
Yes.
I remember you usually use
a pillow made with gold thread woven through it.
How come you're using this other pillow now?
Lumière, you might not know
that because Consort Oriole is pregnant now,
the pillow made with gold thread
can still feel too rough despite its material.
His Majesty specifically ordered
this pillow with Suzhou embroidery
so Consort Oriole can have more restful sleep.
The pillow is filled with millet grains,
which is said to be best for nourishing one's energy.
I always used a pillow made of the cloud brocade.
A few days ago,
His Majesty awarded me a pillow with
a dark flower pattern embroidered with gold threads.
I love it so much.
After all, my skin is thick and rough
and cannot feel the coarseness of gold threads.
The tea is so aromatic.
What my palace has is not even half as good.
You must be joking.
What I have
is never comparable to yours.
It's fortunate that you're willing to accept my poor offerings.
Now that you're pregnant,
why are you still using such strong incense?
It's better to be careful.
Especially musk.
You love creating incense. Don't make any mistakes.
You're overthinking, Lumière.
The incense is made from the juice of fresh flowers.
How can I afford to use precious spices like musk?
You can say what you want,
but this satin, it's called moon shadow satin.
It's a precious and exotic tribute.
One piece of it is worth at least a hundred taels of gold.
Hanging in the chamber,
it renders sunlight as soft as the light of the moon.
Just looking at your chamber, it is worth
at least tens of thousands of gold taels.
Ask yourself,
how can other palaces compare with yours?
Obviously, His Majesty cherishes you so much.
Isn't that so?
His Majesty thinks so highly of Consort Oriole's pregnancy.
Lumière, if you like, I can give them to you.
Please do accept them.
I can't accept gifts meant for you.
Speaking of which,
I'm here to congratulate your pregnancy,
as well as your promotion to Consort.
Xiao-Yunzi, come.
Yes.
This fan is made of pale jade and is the best for summer.
The handle always stays cool to the touch.
These rubies are raw and uncut.
You can ask the skilled craftsmen to decorate a coronet with them.
All the gifts are so unique.
The "pigeon's blood" ruby is so pure and brightly colored;
there is no impurity within it at all.
It is so gorgeous.
How can I accept such expensive gifts from you, Lumière?
You are the jewel in His Majesty's crown.
Anything less than these
is not worthy of you.
Is the doctor for Consort Oriole's prenatal care here?
Your Noble Highness,
it is Dr. Xu.
I greet Noble Highness Lumière.
Since you are now pregnant,
you must exercise extra care in everything.
Just like what Her Majesty the Empress said,
you must avoid the misery of miscarriage like me.
All items from anyone must be carefully examined,
including my gifts today,
Lumière, please don't speak as if we were strangers.
I do not deserve you saying that.
If I have a shred of suspicion against you,
I must be...
Don't say it! There are taboos.
I am doing this for the sake of our sisterhood.
If anyone wants to tamper with my gifts,
they will have no chance to do so.
Actually...
This is Dr. Wei.
Examination by two doctors will set my mind completely at ease.
Your Highness,
there is nothing harmful to the prenatal qi in these presents.
Agreed.
Then both of us can put our minds at ease.
Lingrong, it hasn't been easy for you to get pregnant.
You must nourish yourself well.
Since Dr. Wei is here today,
how about letting him take your pulse,
so we can all feel assured?
Thank you for your concern.
I should take your advice to have another pulse-taking,
but Dr. Xu was recommended by Her Majesty.
While I feel the same way about having more assurance,
if Her Majesty finds out about this,
she might misunderstand and think we question Dr. Xu's proficiency.
Then, Dr. Xu, how is Lady Oriole's prenatal qi?
Oh, Lady Oriole's prenatal qi is very stable.
Your Highness can tell through her glowing complexion.
Is there any problem with Consort Oriole using incense?
That's fine.
Lingrong, you are good at making incense.
I wonder what you are using today?
It's called the Condensed Dew.
If you like it,
I can give you some as a gift.
Coua, take some from my incense box
and pack it up well for Noble Highness Lumière.
Yes.
How can I order your personal maid around?
Xiao-Yunzi.
Yes.
Follow Coua to get the incense.
Did you notice anything wrong?
It's hard to tell right now,
but I do have doubts about something.
Your Highness, I can't be sure yet.
After I confirm, I will report to Your Highness.
When I was there to fetch the Condensed Dew incense,
I saw some incense boxes put on high shelves.
She said Consort Oriole put them away
because she no longer likes them.
However, those boxes were so delicately painted,
they didn't look like unwanted items.
When Coua wasn't paying attention, I pried open a box and took a bit.
They seem to be incense cones.
The aroma is really strange.
What is that?
I called you because I wanted to ask one thing.
Is Consort Oriole's prenatal qi stable?
Your Noble Highness,
as you presumed,
Consort Oriole probably won't be able to deliver the baby.
How do you know I presumed
that her baby cannot be delivered?
Defaming me is not a minor offense.
I don't dare.
Dr. Xu who checks Consort Oriole's pulse
already reported her pregnancy is stable.
If Your Highness believed that,
you wouldn't come ask me.
Rise and speak.
I thank Your Highness.
You know I have doubts,
so just tell me the truth.
I privately checked her pulse-taking records.
It's written that her pulse condition is moderate
and normal prenatal formulas are prescribed.
But in the herbs,
they added mugwort leaf, skullcap, zhumagen,
and baizhu.
I don't know about the other herbs,
but isn't mugwort for soothing the menstrual flow and stopping bleeding?
One must not use it unless strictly necessary.
Your Highness is wise.
The other day, even though Consort Oriole lit incense in her palace,
which covered the smell of burning mugwort leaves,
I still noticed traces of burnt mugwort.
She has already started using mugwort leaves in the fourth month.
It can be inferred that she has experienced bleeding.
Besides, huangqin, zhumagen, and baizhu
also stop bleeding and restore qi.
This shows that Consort Oriole already has qi and blood deficiencies,
and suffers from night sweats and "slippery fetus."
I have also heard that
Consort Oriole has been dispirited lately.
I'm afraid as her months grow,
her pregnancy will become more precarious.
There's no chance of a full-term pregnancy.
There is always a possibility.
If all imperial doctors do their best,
perhaps Consort Oriole can still have a smooth delivery.
Consort Oriole is using mugwort leaves.
She already knows she can't have the baby.
If she really can't keep it,
who does Your Highness think will be held responsible for that?
It's no matter if she herself can't keep it.
But if someone happens to collide with her,
it will be their bad luck.
Only you and I should know this.
Surely I will bear no responsibility for it.
Take a look, what is this?
Jinxi.
Forgive me Your Highness, I was too careless.
I didn't know this incense was so powerful.
What is it?
It's stimulating incense for intimate affairs.
Only a tiny amount was dissolved,
yet it's this strong.
Your Highness is not aware
the ylang-ylang and snake's bed seeds in the incense
are exceedingly concentrated.
If it's burnt, the effect would be even more powerful.
Therefore, when it's in use,
only a tiny amount
needs to be mixed with other incense to be effective.
And it would be hard to notice that way.
Ylang-ylang has the effect of arousing sensual desires.
What happens if ylang-ylang is
mixed with the Goose Pear Bedside Incense?
Same effect, just not as powerful as using this incense alone.
Your Highness, ylang-ylang is harmless in nature,
but in this incense, the ingredient
has been immensely concentrated.
Your Highness may know that ylang-ylang is rarely available in the palace.
Whoever has this incense would maintain favor year after year.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Phoenix Taking Flight
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
The dreams I dimly recall;
The past I hardly remember,
amidst the autumn moons and the spring flowers.
Like the moon's reflection on water
or flowers seen through mist - floating and drifting.
The joyous sounds you brought;
The silence you left;
Changing faster than clouds can turn to rain.
Our minds resonated;
Our hearts beat in unison;
But we lost what we once possessed.
A poem to converse;
A melody to accompany;
A heart to bind to mine.
I hoped for endless longing and eternal promise,
but I’m left with only the flute and the zither.
With affection, I pleased;
With my heart, I committed;
With my arms, I embraced.
I desired to be remembered;
Desired to be cherished;
Why am I only hated and deceived?
My wish ran against my will.
Behold the mockery of destiny and the game of fate.
My unwavering love is gone
like flowers swept away in the wind.
Praying for a bright moon;
Praying for a rising sun;
Dreaming to bask in the spring breezes.
But the unsparing northern winds carry snow and rain
to destroy the aspirations of the plum tree.
A phoenix about to take flight rustles its wings
but the arc of its flight is unseen.
The phoenix tree sways in the wind,
shedding memories in the whispers of the falling leaves.